Sampath Mestha

Frontend Developer

Email: sampathmestha@gmail.com

Bangalore +91 8497818677 LinkedIn Github Udemy Certificates

PROFILES

Experienced Frontend Developer with 1+ years of experience in creating responsive user applications and websites. Proficient in using React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS to develop effective user interfaces according to client requirements. Experience in designing web applications with different tools related to the React platform.

EXPERIENCE

SearchBlox Software Inc, Remote — Front end Developer

Sep 2022 - PRESENT

- Working with the SearchBlox search platform for UI templates/updates.
- Creating/Updating ReactJS Search UI templates for customers.
- Created many responsive and reusable components for future use and monitoring & maintaining front-end performance.
- Troubleshooting & debugging to boost the overall performance.

SocioClub, Remote — Front end Developer, **Intern**

Jun 2022 - Aug 2022

- Worked on creating responsive web pages to cater to multiple media devices. and Built reusable components with ReactJS.
- Worked on images for alignment within the application.

EDUCATION

St. Aloysius College (Autonomous), Mangalore — *BCA* Bachelor of Computer Applications

Jun 2019 - Jun 2022 CGPA - 8/10

SKILLS - Major

React

JavaScript

HTML5

CSS3

Redux

Tailwind CSS

SKILLS - Familiar with

NextIS

TypeScript

NodeJS

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Kannada

UDEMY CERTIFICATIONS

Micro-Frontend

UI Accessability

NextIS

NodeJS